Empresses in the Palace—the Legend of Zhen Huan
Adapted from the novel by Liu Lian Zi
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Subscription: liberapay.com/ZHZSubbers
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Theme: Unfortunate Love
Perturbed by the thoughts on my mind
no matter how hard I try to sever my love.
I could give away my crown for the beauty by my side,
but the wheel of fortune turns weals into woes,
and woes into weals.
No one is the master of their own destiny,
the vicissitudes throughout their life.
For the lovers of all time,
who can break the spell of romance?
I could give away my crown for the beauty by my side,
but the wheel of fortune turns weals into woes,
and woes into weals.
No one is the master of their own destiny,
the vicissitudes throughout their life.
For the lovers of all time,
who can break the spell of romance?
Who can break the spell of romance?
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Subscription: liberapay.com/ZHZSubbers
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
The Household Department has done a decent job.
This set of nail guards are stylish and magnificent.
Why would anyone not do their utmost to serve Your Highness?
The servants worked hard because they dare not offend me.
What matters is not the title granted by His Majesty,
but the heart of His Majesty.
His Majesty has promoted Consort Estime
but he is still not fond of her.
Let alone the Empress. She is old like "a pearl turning yellow".
She is the Empress only because she is related to the Empress Dowager.
Exactly.
His Majesty was never affectionate with her
even before we moved into the palace.
And now it's only getting worse.
Your Highness,
Dr. Jiang is here for the routine pulse-taking.
Yes.
Yes, Your Highness.
Peace to Your Highness.
You may rise.
Thank you for coming.
Your Highness is in good health.
If so, when will I have prenatal qi?
Even Lady Fuca has gotten pregnant.
Your Highness's health was affected by the miscarriage four years ago
and has been gradually restored through careful treatment.
The good news is just a matter of time.
In the meantime, Your Highness must take good care of your health.
Thank you for your kind words. I wish Heaven would comply.
How's everything at the Imperial Infirmary?
Graced by Your Highness, everything is good.
I wouldn't have reached this day without you and your brother.
I won't treat you two unfairly.
We are both aware of how the plague remedy was obtained.
Exercise prudence at work.
I understand, Your Highness.
In order to save mine and my brother's lives,
I had to make an unwise decision.
I entreat Your Highness’s pardon.
As long as it serves the purpose,
I don't mind the means and methods.
Don’t worry too much.
Was Dr. Wen Shichu suspicious of anything?
It wouldn't matter even if he was.
Although he has outstanding medical skills
he has only a junior position at the Imperial Infirmary.
Without evidence, he must stay quiet about it .
That's good. You can go now.
Why do you always look upset after visiting Consort Fleur.
What do you know?
About what?
We have become prominent in the Imperial Infirmary
and we are in Consort Fleur's favor.
We can count on making a name for ourselves.
Making a name for ourselves?
That is a name for someone with integrity and morality.
Mind your tongue and do your work.
Don't worry about anything beyond your job.
That is the way to survive in the palace.
I bow in respect before Your Majesty.
May peace and grace be with Your Majesty.
All rise. Have a seat.
I thank Your Majesty.
Why is Attendant An absent again?
Lingrong hasn't recovered from her cough.
The doctors advised her to avoid going out.
That's why she cannot pay respects to Your Majesty.
Attendant An's health is vulnerable.
It is best for her to stay put until
the plague is completely stopped.
I thank Your Majesty for your consideration.
Have all the stipends been paid for the month?
They have.
I've checked the account books from the Household Department.
Consort Fleur, are you clear about the other expenses?
The stipend for each concubine was
stipulated by our imperial ancestors.
There is absolutely no mistake.
Was it reviewed by Consort Estime?
There's no need for that.
The accounts I reconciled are absolutely correct.
Consort Estime is unfamiliar with the expenses.
It will only delay stipend payments and raise complaints from the harem.
Your Majesty,
I am slow on reviewing the account book.
I will study it to avoid any delays.
You will study it? How much time do you need?
How much of a delay would be caused while you study it?
You don't have the aptitude for such a big responsibility.
The servants would laugh at your sluggishness and incompetence.
Lady Fuca, did you have morning sickness today?
I always feel nauseous when I get up
and after each meal.
It's exhausting.
Eat less if you feel nauseous.
You asked the Imperial Kitchen to serve food "like running water."
Of course you would eat and vomit
and feel sick all day.
Pregnancy is hard work for nine months.
Your health takes priority.
You should eat whatever you want.
Having another heir is joyful news for the imperial family.
Now everyone has their eyes and minds on your pregnant belly.
I thank Your Majesty.
I will always remember Your Majesty's advice.
I don't mind Consort Fleur accusing me of an increased appetite.
Your Highness cannot understand the difficulty in carrying a child.
I have not only carried an imperial heir
but also seen many expectant concubines in the palace.
You've been flaunting your child as if it were a golden ingot.
What a small minded woman!
All right, refrain yourselves.
Lady Fuca,
it would be wonderful if you are pregnant with a prince.
His Majesty does not have many sons.
You can count on a promotion if you give birth to a prince.
You must take care of your health for you and your child.
Yes.
This powder was recently made by the Household Department.
His Majesty ordered them to prepare it especially for me before he left.
Yes, My Lady.
His Majesty said since you are pregnant
and Attendant An is recovering from a cough,
Spices used in the Palace of Prolonging Happiness must be strictly selected.
Musk is forbidden, and calming ingredients are added.
The imperial doctors have examined these powders
and assured they are safe for pregnancy.
How blessed you are!
His Majesty cares a lot about you.
I have luck on my side.
But Attendant An next door has a bad cough.
She's been coughing like "the messenger of Death".
Coua, what made you so happy ?
My Lady, I thought you went to visit Attendant Chun.
Why are you back already?
What did you do?
I didn't do anything.
Show me your hands.
Show me!
Why are your hands dusty?
Incense ashes?
I just couldn't bear Lady Fuca bullying you, My Lady.
I heard that incense ashes mixed with horse urine
can bring bad luck to someone if doused at their walls.
I did it only because she's unbearable.
Are you out of your mind?
How can you believe in such a ridiculous superstition?
My Lady, it's all my fault.
I ask for your punishment if you are angry, My Lady.
I will take all the punishment myself if you take me to Lady Fuca.
Rise.
You are my personal maid.
There's no difference to others whether you did it or I did it.
I've also been hoping the flames of her arrogance would die down.
You did just what I've wanted to do.
My Lady ...
You have long been in my service
and have started to share my thoughts,
haven't you?
What you do and say now
is a reflection of my will.
Just as Autumn is Her Majesty's,
and Vermilion reflects Sourire's.
Did I do anything wrong, My Lady?
Not at all.
You simply did what a loyal servant would do.
Peace to Lady Sourire.
Why are you out of bed?
Do you feel better today?
I do.
Lady Vertu's health has improved greatly.
But she needs a lot of rest for a full recovery.
Thank you so much, Dr. Wen.
I wouldn't have recovered without your help.
My Lady, there’s something that confuses me.
Yes.
Don’t you think it was an abrupt infection?
I remembered that the first case of the
disease was reported in Consort Fleur’s palace.
And immediately after that was you.
Since you were not in contact with any servants from
Consort Fleur’s palace during the confinement,
how did you contract the plague?
Do you suspect that they deliberately spread the disease to kill me?
It's just a suspicion that I had.
Meizhuang, if you think back to when it happened,
was there anything odd?
My Lady, the Household Department sends you a new tea set.
The tea has been made for you, My Lady.
Lunar.
My Lady.
Was my tea set changed?
Yes, My Lady.
Because the disease is infectious, everything you used,
especially the tableware, has been smashed and buried.
You can go now.
Yes.
I remember that before I was infected,
Zhou Ninghai sent me a new tea set.
He told me it was from the Household Department.
The tea set didn't look like it was made for a concubine.
I didn't argue with him considering I was in confinement.
So I used it.
The disease is highly infectious.
To prevent it from spreading,
people must avoid physical contact
with the patients and not use their utensils.
Especially drinking from the same teaware.
Was the tea set that Zhou Ninghai sent used by a patient?
I’m afraid so.
Yes, it was!
It was not the first time that she tried to kill me.
It was her! It was her again!
Meizhuang, you have to calm down.
We need evidence for this.
There’s also one thing I don’t understand.
Jiang Cheng and Jiang Shen are specialists in gynecology.
How did they suddenly master the knowledge of epidemics?
If I say their remedy was mostly my work,
would you believe me, My Lady?
I do. You are capable of that work.
But how did they get your formula?
I was thinking over a few herbs
after I wrote down most of the prescription.
I dared not issue the prescription immediately
and put it in my drawer in the Imperial Infirmary.
I assume they took my notes for themselves
when I was busy taking care of Lady Vertu.
They may also have added some other herbs into it.
However, they have not specialized in contagions
and prescribed too harsh herbs.
The herbs I selected for Lady Vertu
are milder and more nourishing.
Since His Majesty has already recognized their contribution,
I doubt if anyone would believe you now.
Instead, they might say that you are trying to claim the credit.
Don’t worry. I will speak for you.
What's so interesting about sorting the threads?
As Li Yu says, "worthless if cut apart but messy to unravel."
It's a good pastime for when I have time to myself.
Don't burn daylight when you're young.
You should spend more time with His Majesty.
Life in the Palace is lonely.
Spending time with Your Majesty brings peace to my mind.
You've been coming to the Palace of
Great Benevolence more frequently these days.
Why don't you visit Lady Sourire and
Attendant Chun at the Palace of Pearl Jade?
Your Majesty doesn't enjoy my company?
I do. You are quiet and smart.
But everyone likes to be in a lively place.
Why would you prefer my palace, which is quiet all day?
The quietness teaches me to endure loneliness.
Your Majesty’s noble temperament is like
the clouds above the mountain tops.
It inspires awe in me.
Besides, I should avoid crowded places
when I'm recovering from the cough.
This so-called noble temperament, or calm forbearance,
is born from immersion in quietness and loneliness.
I misspoke. I didn’t mean to imply anything like that.
Rise.
Of course I know you didn’t mean that.
Between us, unnecessary words need not be spoken.
I thank Your Majesty.
Oh, I made a sachet and wish to present it to Your Majesty.
I hope Your Majesty will not be troubled by my coarse handwork.
This sachet is exquisite.
It smells light and elegant.
It contains peony and orchid petals,
mixed with agarwood and pine needles.
It smells light at first.
It takes some time to discern the graceful scent
of peony which seeps into your heart.
The embroidery pattern is also my favorite
—Phoenix Above Peonies.
[Both are symbols of an empress]
It would be a great honor if Your Majesty likes it.
I do, but I'm afraid I will not use it.
I never use spices and perfumes.
I did not notice.
Every time I pay respects to Your Majesty,
I remember the palace is perfumed by flowers and fresh fruits.
I wasn't aware that Your Majesty dislikes spices.
I should have been more thoughtful.
I don’t dislike spices.
I'm reminding you that certain spices will do harm if misused.
I thank Your Majesty for the advice.
You know the use of different spices,
and should be aware of their harm and good.
Cats do like to howl in the spring.
But unlike other cats, my Pine Nut likes to pounce on things.
It's hard to pacify a cat in spring heat.
But cats like to follow scents.
They will be obedient once they have been trained with scents.
You are a master of the art of scents, Attendant An.
Little wonder you thought of this method.
I will do my utmost to prepare a scent which will help train Pine Nut.
It will only take a few days.
Very well.
The flowers have come into bloom
in the Palace of Great Benevolence.
I would like to invite all the concubines
over to share the joy of the spring.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Subscription: liberapay.com/ZHZSubbers
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
They smell so sweet.
My Lady, there are a lot of flowers over there.
Your Majesty's palace is the warmest.
The flowers here bloom the earliest and the brightest.
The Palace of Great Benevolence is blessed by Earth
while your palace is blessed by Heaven.
It has already been four months, hasn't it?
It has.
The imperial doctors said I'm in a more
stable stage of pregnancy after the first four months.
I had severe symptoms when I was
pregnant with the Third Prince.
My swelling feet couldn't even fit into my shoes.
But you don't seem to have this problem.
I heard that the Third Prince was well and active
when Consort Astuce was pregnant.
That's why he has an impetuous temper now.
It takes His Majesty quite a bit of effort to teach him.
You ...
I agree.
Only Consort Astuce has the strength to carry an active child.
Consort Fleur is too fragile to go through the hardship of pregnancy.
I hope you're having a prince.
A princess will be such a waste of your arrogance.
Lady Fuca, you shouldn't be standing for too long.
- Autumn.
- Yes.
I grant Lady Fuca a seat in the garden.
Place a goose feather cushion to keep her seat warm.
Yes, Your Majesty.
I thank Your Majesty.
May peace be with you, Fuca.
Your powder smells like the sweet dew.
It doesn't look like the typical powder we use in the palace.
Doesn't Lady Sourire have a good sense of smell?
His Majesty ordered it from the
Household Department specifically for me.
It's not only moisturizing but also harmless to the child.
That's a rarity indeed.
His Majesty is very considerate towards you.
If Lady Sourire is fond of this powder,
I can give some to you.
His Majesty specially had it made for you.
It would be inappropriate for me to take it.
That's true.
After all, this is a token of affection from His Majesty.
Since you are being courteous,
I won't oblige you to accept this.
Since this is a gift from his Majesty,
Lady Fuca must put it away for safekeeping.
Better yet, you should place it on an altar and offer incense to it.
The wind and the sun will wear down His Majesty's
token of affection if you put it on your face.
Let's go, Sourire.
As if no one else had ever been pregnant.
Who does she think she is?
It's all right, Attendant Joie.
Lady Fuca is now in the limelight.
There is no need to get angry over her.
Peace and grace to Your Majesty.
Attendant Joie, what were you talking about?
Joie was just saying how nice the weather is today.
It's a nice day today.
Why doesn't Your Majesty bring Pine Nut out here?
Consort Qi has always been so fond of Pine Nut.
You always want to hold him when you are here.
But Lady Sourire is afraid of cats.
Still, I guess it will be fine.
Autumn, go bring Pine Nut out here.
I dare not touch him.
He's heavier and grumpier in spring.
I wonder where he is right now.
We were just talking about Pine Nut,
and he came out himself.
Your Majesty has been taking really good care of Pine Nut.
He's gotten bigger.
While everyone else keep cats and dogs,
Consort Estime is into unusual pets.
She keeps a really big tortoise in her glass tank!
I was thinking to have an effortless pet.
A tortoise is quiet and easy to feed.
I'm too clumsy to keep other pets.
If Consort Estime considers herself "clumsy",
then I wouldn't have a word to describe myself.
Concubine Estime has not been promoted officially.
Is it too fawning for Lady Sourire to call her "Consort"?
You have all the time in the future to call her "Consort".
Consort Fleur, don't be so serious.
Does it matter whether she has been officially promoted?
His Majesty has affirmed her title, so now she is a Consort,
isn't she?
She is who she is, and she isn't who she isn't.
A blessed concubine would not fear the wait.
But without Heaven's blessing,
she could still fail at the last moment.
It's already the third day of this month.
The promotion ceremony will be held in about ten days.
Consort Estime, you must be well-prepared for that.
Yes.
Consort Estime and Consort Fleur were
married into the family on the same day.
Now Estime is not only promoted to Consort,
but will also assist you in the palace affairs.
It's fortunate to have someone's assistance.
And I'm the luckiest one to be enjoying the spring at leisure.
Your Majesty is most blessed by Heaven.
The mudan peonies are beautiful in full bloom.
But pink is an inferior color after all.
They will never be suitable for a grand occasion.
Unlike the shaoyao peonies.
They are not the queen of flowers but are a vibrant red.
This is the proper color for the primary wife.
Pink is only used by concubines.
Only pure red and this magenta red
are worthy of the primary wife.
But, as long as the wife is young,
does it matter what color of flower she wears?
What a twisted perversion of status!
Your Majesty, I remember a poem I learned in my childhood.
It is befitting to the occasion.
I hope Your Majesty and Your Highnesses
will allow me to recite it before you.
Go ahead.
The shaoyao in the garden are pretty but styleless.
The lotus on the pond are elegant but unromantic.
Only mudan, in the color of the nation,
draws the city to admire her blossoms.
What an admirer of the color of the nation!
Respect for superiority is in people's hearts.
No matter how pretty the shaoyao is, it is of no style after all.
It can't compare to the stately color and fragrance of mudan.
Consort Fleur, we're here today to enjoy the flowers.
Why do you look unhappy?
Please don't be so sensitive.
Fuca, your makeup has run while you have been sitting in the garden.
The powder that His Majesty granted you smells really sweet.
What's going on?
My Lady!
Send for the doctors!
Are you all right, My Lady?
How are you?
It hurts!
- Are you all right, My Lady?
- She got scratched by Pine Nut.
Your Majesty, I'm hurting!
Send for the doctors immediately!
Help Lady Fuca to go rest in the side chamber!
Sourire, if you got hurt, I …
Fuca, are you all right?
Help her up quickly.
Sourire, don’t scare me.
How are you feeling?
Your Majesty, it hurts so much!
The imperial doctors will be here in no time. Don’t worry!
I beg Your Majesty’s pardon for my delay.
Finally you are here.
Dr. Zhang, go check on Lady Fuca!
Yes.
Your Majesty, Lady Fuca has an unstable pulse after the fall.
Her prenatal qi is affected and she is in shock.
I suggest that Lady Fuca be sent back to
her own residence for immediate treatment.
I'll prescribe medications to see if her prenatal qi can be restored.
Go write the prescriptions immediately.
Yes.
Peace to Your Majesty.
All rise.
I thank Your Majesty.
I came as soon as I heard about it.
How is Lady Fuca?
The doctor has prescribed medicine for her.
Hurts ...
Your Majesties,
Lady Fuca is bleeding.
It's too late now.
How could this happen?
Your Majesty,
Lady Fuca was unfortunately pounced on by a cat in heat.
She was frightened then knocked down.
Where is the brute?
I've sent people to catch it.
Who owns such a verminous cat?
I beg Your Majesty's forgiveness.
The cat is named Pine Nut.
Consort Astuce gave it to me and I kept it as a pet.
Pine Nut has always been very well-behaved.
But he suddenly went wild today.
It is all my fault.
Rise.
Yes.
Send Lady Fuca back immediately on a soft sedan.
It's not necessary for her to stay in your palace.
Order the doctors to do their best
and see if the imperial heir can be saved.
Everything else will be decided by Heaven.
Yes.
What happened to Lady Sourire?
Lady Sourire stumbled when she was trying to save Lady Fuca.
She must have gotten injured from that.
Doctor, you should check on Lady Sourire.
Yes.
Your Majesty,
The scratches on Lady Sourire's neck are superficial.
She will just need to apply some ointment.
But her left arm must be taken good care of.
Doctor, can you take her pulse so we can all be assured?
Yes. Allow me, My Lady.
Congratulations, My Lady!
What are you talking about?
Sourire has just got her arm injured.
Congratulations, My Lady!
You've been with child for almost two months.
That's wonderful news!
Don't move. Don't move.
Sit down. Sit.
Dr. Zhang,
Are you certain that Lady Sourire is pregnant?
I have been practicing medicine for several decades.
I am confident about the pregnancy diagnosis.
Your Majesty, Lady Sourire's health is in a vulnerable state.
And her pregnancy vital signs have been affected by the fall.
I will prescribe herbal tonics to improve her prenatal health.
Everything will be fine after having some rest.
Thank you, Dr. Zhang.
I am putting the health of Lady Sourire and her child in your care.
I will do my utmost.
Dr. Zhang is an experienced doctor. Don't worry.
Dr. Zhang, please go attend to Lady Fuca for now.
- Spring.
- Yes.
Send for more doctors to assist Dr. Zhang.
Yes, Your Majesty.
I thank Your Majesty for your kind consideration.
I am eternally grateful.
What a timely pregnancy!
While Lady Fuca's pregnancy is unfortunately failing,
you're fortunate to have yours.
What happened today is truly unexpected.
However, Lady Sourire, you were so careless.
You were unaware of your own pregnancy,
and even threw yourself down to save another.
It's fortunate that you didn't get hurt.
No accident should happen to the heirs of the imperial family.
I apologize to Your Majesty.
Your servants have been very careless.
How could they not have noticed your pregnancy?
If an accident had happened today,
they would all be banished to the Department of Penalty.
Your Majesty must not be mad at them.
None of them are at fault.
I am the careless one.
I thought it was just springtime fatigue.
I've also been having irregular menstrual cycles.
I know that everyone else
felt nauseous when they were pregnant
But I didn't have any symptoms.
Pregnancy symptoms are naturally different for everyone.
When I was pregnant with Wenyi,
I didn't have any symptoms until four months in.
Your Majesty, His Majesty doesn't have many children yet.
Now that Lady Sourire is pregnant,
this is Heaven's blessing for our country.
The first trimester is the most important.
You must take care of your health
especially after you just got injured.
Yes, I thank Your Majesty.
All right, stop looking at it.
The doctor has said the injury is superficial.
I wonder if it will leave a scar.
It would just be a small scar at most,
not even noticeable when covered with powder.
You are all right and that's all that matters.
True. It's fortunate that my child is not affected.
Vermilion, go get some water.
Yes.
Jade, get two more comfortable pillows for Sourire to lean on.
Jinxi, close the doors. It's windy outside.
Yes.
Xiao-Yunzi, get the cloud silk blanket.
It's all right.
I am not that fragile. Don't make them bustle around.
All right.
You are pregnant. You need a quiet place to rest.
You shall all leave.
Now that you sent them all away,
who will take care of me?
I will, is that all right?
Your health has just been restored.
You shouldn't be taking care of me.
Huan'er, I am truly happy for you.
But today, Lady Fuca lost her child,
and His Majesty hasn't come back yet.
That makes me worried about you.
I won't let anything happen to my child.
You certainly won't.
And Lady Fuca wouldn't want anything to happen to her child.
I have to tell you that
miscarriages are all too common in the harem.
I have asked the doctors
and they told me Attendant Joie lost her child
because she accidentally slipped and fell.
Lady Fuca also had an accident.
Do you feel that
all these "accidents" are in fact not accidents?
How is Lady Fuca now?
She has been moved back to the Palace of Prolonging Happiness.
She was unconscious when I went to visit.
All the doctors were there.
My lady, let's go inside. This gives me the creeps.
Why?
No one will be able to sleep tonight with the palace in such an uproar.
Even the night is colored and perfumed by the flowers in March.
My lady, I left the corner door open per your bidding.
Will Consort Honnête really come?
Consort Honnête always keeps her word.
She will come since she has informed us that she will.
My lady, I was frightened when you
threw yourself out to save Lady Fuca.
It was too dangerous.
You are not very close to Lady Fuca.
Why would you do that?
If I say someone pushed me towards Lady Fuca,
do you believe that?
I guess whoever pushed me intended to
make me knock into Lady Fuca's stomach.
So I would be the culprit for her miscarriage.
"Kill two hawks with one arrow".
Of all the concubines in the harem,
the pregnant one is always "the target of all the arrows".
Today, it was Lady Fuca.
The next would be you, My Lady.
I'm afraid this is a sleepless night for many.
Indeed.
Whoever was losing sleep because of Lady Fuca's pregnancy
thought that they would have a good night's sleep tonight.
But now they will be tossing and turning,
thinking about you, My Lady.
I summoned you at this hour because I couldn't sleep.
Neither could I.
I will keep you company, Imperial Mother.
I heard that since Lady Fuca woke up and found out about her child,
she's been crying and screaming in her palace.
She will get over it after she vents her frustration.
Is the brute still not captured?
I have done all I can.
You would even leave such a trivial matter to me.
Bamboo.
Your Majesty.
Is everything ready?
Yes.
Bring it in.
Look carefully.
Lady Sourire, have a look at this.
Although there's no powder left in the box,
I still recognize the smell.
The powder belongs to Lady Fuca.
I have also seen the maids of Lady Fuca taking it out.
Did Your Highness obtain it from Her Majesty's garden?
Exactly.
When everyone was busy looking after you and Lady Fuca,
I picked it up in the garden.
Is Your Highness suspicious of something?
I heard that Lady Fuca had the miscarriage
because the cat Pine Nut jumped at her.
Don't you think it's strange?
Of course, cats are often agitated in spring.
But Pine Nut has been trained well.
Why would it suddenly attack a person?
And why only Lady Fuca?
Maybe ... It was a coincidence?
See, even you said it with hesitation.
You don't believe that either.
So what does Your Highness think?
How much powder can Lady Fuca alone possibly use?
Your Majesty ...
And you are dumping the blame on a cat?
My eyes don't see clearly.
But I'm not blind!
At least I can see with my heart
that it was my grandchild the cat killed!
I beg Your Majesty's forgiveness.
I have never been the Empress in my life.
I wasn't promoted until the death of the prior emperor.
That was why I made you the Empress after the emperor's coronation.
I did that to secure the throne of the Empress in our family.
Remember,
I can turn a blind eye to some things,
but not to others.
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Subscription: liberapay.com/ZHZSubbers
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Theme: The Lonely Phoenix
[phoenix is the symbol of an empress]
I dimly recall the colorful blooms in every summer.
They are as distant as the autumn moon in the water.
He loved me with a volatile heart.
And before I knew it, we fell apart.
Behind me are the promises and longing.
Before me lie the flute and the zither.
I loved you with my body and soul
But you hurt me from head to toe.
My wish ran athwart
and I ended up a fool of my destiny.
My love was the wind-swept flowers from a tree.
A plum bloomed in winter hoping for a fruitful summer.
But the irresistible winds of destiny destroyed her wish.
You can hear the flapping of a phoenix
but you will never see it.
What you see is the falling leaves from the phoenix tree.
The falling leaves from the phoenix tree.